When you're looking to create like
really complex software using LLM, it's
important to take away as much of the
complexity from the LLM as possible. If
you would need to give like a very long
and complex speech, obviously it will be
easier to speak at your native language.
Every large organization has tons of
software needs. Think of an organization
like Pepsi or something like that,
right? The more that you build tools,
the more that you build automations, the
more that the business becomes more
efficient. When you build a web app in B
44, you already have everything you need
to make it functional. User management,
a database integrations with sending
emails or leveraging LLMs and analytics
and logs and all those kind of things.
>> So with all of these advancements and
all the capabilities that B 44 is
building, like what's your prediction
about how long does it take till you can
build a base 44 with B 44? Um
[Music]
hello everyone. Welcome back to the AI
native dev. Uh today we have a really
fun episode where we'll talk a little
bit about sort of startups and
entrepreneurship. We'll talk about uh
building uh in in sort of AI powered
ways and five coding and kind of this
brave new world, but also how do you
actually build a company uh and uh and
use AI to uh to make that a possibility.
And to talk about all of that, we have
Mo Lammo, who is the founder of B 44.
Tell us a little bit about what B 44 is
and what was different about how you
built it or not how you built it, but
rather the thing that you built.
>> Um, B 44 is is an AI app builder. Uh,
kind of like the text to app that you
see a lot these days. uh I think we're
taking a very different approach, a very
opinionated approach which is uh help
people build actual full stack
functional applications. So sometimes
the way I like to put it in perspective
is saying vibe coding has been awesome
at first um for building websites and
building user interfaces and some MVPs
like mainly front end. Um and then B 44
was I think the first one but maybe one
of the first ones to introduce this
concept of uh batteries included app
builder which means that when you build
a web app in B 44 you already have
everything you need to make it
functional already built in. So user
management, the database integrations
with like sending emails or leveraging
LLMs and analytics and logs and all
those kind of things that you need when
you're actually building a fully
functional or even complex application.
Uh and that's what B 44 basically does.
It's helping users create software that
either they or their users or customers
are going to use dayto-day. And is it is
it more about the choice of uh the
opinionated stack? Hey, I chose a
database. I chose you know all these
other aspects. Uh or is it uh about the
continuation because I know you also you
know you deploy an application you kind
of handle the operational aspect of it.
uh do they have to go hand in hand? Is
it uh like how do how do you see the uh
the interaction between like the choice
of stack and managing the operation of
it as well?
>> Yeah, I think it's to some degree both.
I think the choice of stack will become
less important throughout times. So like
I can see that with our developer
community as they gain more trust in
like what base 44 does and like the fact
that it's becoming slightly less and
less importance like what's the tax
stack that you're using and how you're
going to handle deployment and those
things. Uh because VIP coding is getting
better. It's not perfect yet. It's still
hard to build production applications. I
think on base 44 it's slightly easier
but there's still a long way to go. Um,
and I think it's like this opinionated
approach is basically trying to correct
the actual experience of how you want
VIP coding to look like. Like you don't
want to start stitching together
different services and say, "Oh, you
know what? Now I want to connect an LLM.
I need to go to OpenAI, bring my API
key, fit it into the VIP coding
platform, and I want to connect the
database. I need to look at the tables
and run migrations and stuff like that."
things that nobody really wants to uh to
deal with or at least in the future I'm
imagining a future where those things
are are entirely being handled uh behind
the scenes and you can just literally
build what you want to build and
literally program in English without
needing to understand again what an API
key is and so on. Um, obviously to do
that we had to take a lot of like
opinionated decisions on the tax deck
and so on.
>> And I'm I'm still curious on how much is
it that you are uh uh picking specific
stacks that you have seen the LLM to be
good at or that you've just really
invested in making LLMs create well with
versus where is it things that you've
just taken out of the LLM's uh domain.
you know, like uh I'll give an example
like in in in Tessle, you know, when we
create software, you know, for a while,
we actually don't need that now, but
used to be that, you know, the LLMs just
wouldn't stick to the dependencies we
told them to do. It's like, hey, create
this code here, use library A and B, and
it would just sort of use B and Z and
whatever. It would invent things. Uh
until eventually, uh we said like, okay,
you're not allowed to choose
dependencies anymore. We'll we'll put
the import A, import B over there, and
you you fill in the rest. Uh we've since
removed that because they got better at
it. But uh but that was like to me like
commandeering control like I guess is it
similar like the LM just has nothing has
no choice has no say in the choice of a
database. You just have to use what
you've been given or is it about
choosing a database that you made it use
very very well. So I think one of the
advantages of building base 44
uh I would say late to the game is the
fact that uh we really designed a lot of
the things around the LLM. So B4
obviously employs a concept called
backend as a service uh which is like
for for the devs probably familiar with
like Firebase or Superbase and so on.
Um, but those are like products that
were built pre the LLM era and had their
own like endpoints and syntax and so on.
And so when when I started base 44 and
started kind like building the first
couple of apps and so you see what the
LLM uh is uh trying to do and in some
places like you try to like limit it
further. So you tell it like hey don't
use those packages and it tries to use
those packages. So, so you like try to I
don't know write in the prompt important
exclamation point exclamation point
exclamation but like don't do that or
the other way around which I think work
really well for us is like just uh uh
run with it like see what the LM is
trying to do when it gets confused and
build it almost in the same syntax that
it's using. So for example, if it's
constantly using like one package over
another and you're trying to use the
other, but there's no real difference
between those two, maybe the the stack
stack will be should be built with
package A. So
>> in some places sometimes it's better to
just uh go with whatever the LLM was
trained on because it will likely bring
you better results. And I think a lot of
the design of our SDK, our backend
services, the packages, the text tech
was more around uh what LLMs are really
good at doing and writing code with.
>> Yeah. And I think this was an important
decision because again when you're
looking to create like really complex
software using LLMs which obviously as
we all know in the space LMS are
struggling with it's important to take
away as much of the complexity from the
LLM as possible and if you can make it
easier so think about it as like think
if you would need to give like a very
long and complex speech right obviously
it will be easier to speak at your
native language So that's what that's
what I tried doing with the LM is like
trying to understand what's the easiest
way for the LLM to create functional
software and then build the text tech
design the SDK design the end points
around that.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it makes a lot of sense and
it sounds like it's a bit of both of the
things that I talked about. there's some
back end as a service that is outside
their the scope of the LLM's decisions
at least as you build a base 44
application
and then on top of that you have the uh
the sort of the choice of stacks that uh
go with uh go with the flow or go with
sort of the uh uh I guess kind of
prevalence and knowledge and the u and
you've uh we're going to talk about your
own tech stack but you've chosen Python
for instance
>> and I'm I'm guessing that's sort of a
similar logic of like Python was the
language the LLM are most proficient at.
>> Yeah. For back end, yeah. Um for front
end, there's also some controversial
decisions that I've taken. So, one of
them is uh LLMs are having an easier
time using writing JavaScript than
writing TypeScript. Uh and they get
confused. Uh so like some of our a lot
of our front end is still written only
in JavaScript which could uh can shake
can shake
>> there are there are firm opinions about
this and in the amidst the technologists
>> yeah I'm sure but also like things
change right like um I think if we get
back to like uh in the places where you
actually limit LLM or you say okay to
okay this is the building block that you
should and and can be used uh like you
should use nothing else besides that. So
yeah, so as you mentioned what you guys
have seen in Tesla is like LM get better
and better or change and adapt and in
some ways like uh even in the the tech
that people build apps in base 44 these
days like as LMS progress we take away
some of the some of those guard rails to
allow the LM more flexibility.
>> Yeah, makes a lot of sense. And the uh
maybe let's just sort of on base 44
still kind of as a user base. So the
target audience of that is is what is
it? Non-developers is it developer
adjacent but technical people? Is it
none of the above? People that are
entirely non-technical. Who did you
build it for?
>> Definitely for the nontechnical people.
Um
the first couple of users were like a
restaurant manager, a marketing guy,
like some of my best friends, right? But
I know their connection to code was uh
something distant. Um but I think what's
surprising to me is that as time goes I
see more and more like there's like a
big community of like developers using
base 44 and obviously as time goes we
we're developing more features for like
semi developers people who do understand
like uh some technicalities.
Uh but I see a future where
where it's like it doesn't matter
anymore. It's like um if you look at
like building a landing page or a just a
landing page, right? Uh think about it
before the age of LLM, right? Um
obviously at some point even if you're a
developer, it would be easier to use Wix
than to code a landing page. Even if you
do know like HTML, PHP whatever and host
it and deploy it and whatever like
nobody wants to do that. Um me myself
even before like before LLMs were like
vibe coding were a big thing I've built
my uh my girlfriend's website using Wix
and I think in some ways for a large
portion of software that that's what
we'll see. So even if you're super
technical, it will be an advantage when
you're vibe coding stuff. Um but it
won't matter that much like it will be
clear that that's an easier choice than
to open up a new GitHub repository,
start writing code, deploy it, run test.
>> Yeah. Why reinvent the wheel when you uh
>> Yeah.
>> But how do you how do you think about so
for the non-technical user trying to
think about the sort of the lines,
right? So if you're uh a developer, I
think a lot of vibe coding, whether it
is in platforms like B 44 or if it's
things that you do more locally, the
cloud code sort of cursors of the world,
um you in in those worlds, you have a
very tight relationship to the code. The
the LLM modifies the agents modify the
code, but when there's a problem, your
sort of supervision happens on the code.
I think in base 44 you can see the code
but it is it is a kind of a hidden
entity or it is not it's not designed to
put the code in your face too much. How
do you how have you seen and what maybe
there's like learnings learnings about
how you have built for people who don't
understand code to be able
>> to to interact and get the system over
the hump when it fails to deliver
something right when it fails to
accomplish something. Is it all just
like give it more guidance, give it more
guidance and and hope it gets it right?
>> Yeah. Um, not only I think the
interaction
when you're building an app in base 44
versus, for example, if you're building
an app using cloud code or cursor, it's
a different interaction and and many
times it's a different user and a lot of
times currently it's a different piece
of software. Mhm.
>> So I'll start with obviously the way
that um
B4's users do iterations and
experimentations and so on has a lot to
do with visual like you see the app in
front of your face. You know if
something is wrong you'll see that in
the interaction or you'll see a bug
being thrown away or something like that
before you even look at the code. Um I
think platforms like base 44 still
there's obviously like a limited set of
software that they can build. Um and
this this set is going to expand further
and further and further as time goes and
that's what we're working on. But it's
still important to be very honest and
say there's a set of software that
you'll be better off building using
Kurser than than than using B 44. Um so
for example base 44 itself put aside the
front end which is obviously built using
B 44 but the back end for B 44 is not
built using B 44 it's like built using
cursor and code and so on
>> um because you need to look at the code
and you need to understand the code and
so
>> this whole thing like this is the
situation and reality right now I think
this is this will aggressively change in
the next few months even but definitely
few years again as as you'll be able to
visually or or like prompts only uh
without looking at the code, you'll be
able to build an increasing
percentage of the software that you're
currently building,
>> right?
>> Um and yeah, and so the tools that we're
giving our users are are a different set
of tools to how how they experiment and
iterate with their software. It has to
do a lot with visual. you have to see
the the the application all the time. It
has to do a lot with trying to explain
better what's going on. So, for example,
we have this uh small feature, but
people really love it where when you
prompt something in base 44 and it
starts coding. So, obviously we like
most of our users don't want to see the
code. It's just it's terrifying for
them. So, they don't understand what's
going on. And so we have another small
LLM that basically watches the coding
agent, see what it does, and kind of
like explains to you in real time like
what's the coding agents currently
doing. And it's like a small like now
it's changing the uh UI from light team
to dark theme and whatever. And so
>> yeah, we're building a set of tools to
help people build software without the
need to look at code.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's so smart. progress
indications and and engagement are super
important. So I think that makes sense
to me. If I echo this back, I feel
you're saying um there sort of the two
domains maybe that base 44 today is most
helpful are cases where a lot of the
validation and a lot of the decisions
are much more product oriented and a lot
more visual specifically oriented uh and
uh as opposed to sort of technical and
how did you implement and the second is
that maybe a lot of them are are places
where that visual is also the innovation
like a lot of the technology you're not
looking to uh make a product that sort
of works that's not some sort of the
world's fanciest progressive web app
that uh does a lot of things. A lot of
your your creation is a lot more about
the content uh and the navigation and
all that might be sort of similar and
common and so the LLMs know how to do it
well and you can do it very efficiently
but you're innovating on sort of the the
content and the looks uh more uh is that
does that sound fair
>> and then it will expand over time?
>> Definitely. But I'll add on top of that,
I think it has more to do with the type
of software that you're building, right?
So if you're building nowadays something
that that's like performance is super
important,
>> right? Like you can't v code your way
through it, like it's like if you're
building, I don't know, a VPN software.
Let's take this for example. Um
>> yeah,
>> so obviously like it's it's going to be
really hard or something that relies
very heavily on like back end and stuff
like that. So
>> previous company probably can't vibe
code sneak.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh at least not yet. uh I think for
other set of applications it's not
necessarily the visuals but more of like
if you're building an application that
that can do what it needs to to do with
a database a set of integrations APIs
and so on um I think like you you'll be
like you can do a really good job using
B 44 and it will likely be an easier
experience than try to code it via
cursor
>> right yeah
>> uh so it has to do with like the
lowlevelness of stuff and complexity on
the back end side. Uh but we are getting
better at that.
>> So uh I have one more question on base
44 but maybe let's first switch to how
you built it. We'll talk about your
stack and then we'll combine a little
bit. I'd like to uh touch a bit on
longevity like building a disposable
app. I think you're creative doing it
versus what do you build for long term?
But take us behind the scenes a sec. So
you've built you know like single person
built substantial platform and also
scaled it. Uh I guess tell us a bit of
the uh of the tips and tricks. I heard
you shared a few of you know what what
helped you uh create that and maybe
started with like do you think you could
have done this? I know you used AI your
creation like was that critical? Do you
feel you could have pulled off a base 44
without AI dev help uh as a builder? Uh
short answer is definitely not. I was at
least not in the same structure and way
that I did it with B 44. So when I
started B 44 even before knowing what I
was going to do, I knew that we're in a
different era. I've been like leveraging
AI, working with AI in my previous
company, both as like AI inside the
product and also coding with AI. Mhm.
>> Um and I felt like I felt strongly that
we're in a new era where doesn't matter
the number of people building software
anymore. more meta about like if you
have a unique take unique product kind
like uh and you can design well like
design software well not I'm not
speaking about like UI design then it's
not anymore about like hey throw as many
people at the problem as you can those
people will write more code faster and
that's where you'll get to so I was like
I'm going to do this alone from day one
I'm going to set up the repository
and spend 20% of my time content
constantly on how can I further uh
increase the velocity and speed. So a
lot of what I did is like
experimentation with how LMS write uh
code better. Obviously I did it for base
44's product as well but but even for my
own repository right so I find those
tips and tricks like what I I've spoken
about like javascript versus typescript
maybe now it's changing with cloud 4 and
so on but back then like I could write
>> uh front ends like the speed of light uh
just because of the setup
>> uh another thing is is I've built this
from the backend side I built this very
high level uh infrastructure
uh that handles like the database and
user management and so on. So that even
if I would have pivoted to a completely
different idea, 80% of the code would
stay the same. And so I had this like
really good infrastructure
um that stayed the same and that's what
those were like the parts of code that
it was slightly more me than the AI
actually writing and making sure that
it's perfect and from there once you
have those infrastructure and so now
adding a new feature that I don't know
has like a new table in a database and
has some integr some interaction with
with other parts of the platform became
super easy. Uh the way I'd measure that
is for the LLM to implement a new
feature, I wanted to write at the least
code possible to implement the feature
end to end. And so I built a lot of like
those things obviously and rules and so
on into the repository so that I could
run on my own but still keep the same
velocity as my competitors if not even
better, faster. And I think I think to
some degree I've done that like I think
the the competitors in this category are
super heavily funded
um and in many ways and aspects base 44
executed
uh extremely fast if not faster than
than a lot of the players in the in the
category
>> and I give a lot of credit to the AI
like most of the credit is to to the AI
of like structuring it
>> for getting me the
>> yeah I want to thank
second Oscar. I get the
>> I think uh so so so I love that. I guess
again kind of echoing back a little bit.
I think you know the first thing you're
sort of touting is like the value of a
good architecture uh where you
anticipate uh what would be future
changes and you write the ability to
write compartmentalized code and I guess
I'm I'm hearing something that is almost
similar like to hiring either junior
developers or outsourcing you know
places in which if you build the right
architecture then you could have clear
instructions to someone else who's maybe
a little bit less trustworthy uh to
write pieces of software within it uh
and be able to assess whether they've
done their job well and be uh I guess
can be able to to guide them. Does that
sound like a fair analogy?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Because also one
one other thing that like I've noticed
is like when you're leveraging AI for
coding so think about it this way like
you let's say you're building like a
simple
full stack web app, right? So, uh, you
tell, hey, I want it to be, um, a to-do
list app or whatever. So, the AI
implements like some of the routes and
connects the front end and so on. And
then you open up a new chat, right, in
carousel or something and you want to
implement another features like write an
admin panel or so on. Uh, so it will
look at your code and it will do the
task, but an AI is really good at that,
but AI is not really good at stop and
saying, "Oh, you know what? There's
actually like common concepts here that
I could like combine to like this
infrastructure or package that I can
later use in other features and oh I'm
writing the same code again and again
like let's stop and before I do like the
the task that you gave me let's kind of
like implement
yeah let's refactor the code so that I
won't need to write as much code and so
on. So I think this is something that a
lot of developers currently don't notice
about AI like it will it will implement
the task as you told it to
>> but it's still lacking the hey let's
stop for a second we need to refactor
the code because I find this common
layer or whatever
>> and I think that's that's
>> and so those that's something you still
did manually like you would observe what
the AI has built and you would kind of
go off and and modify it a lot of a lot
of what we see with AI which I think
touches on the topic you said right now
is is about the initial creation, right?
And it would go off and even there you
sort of see the sort of reward seeking,
right? It might burn down the house to
sort of be able to accomplish this thing
that you've just like break all the
other features, you know, just to be
able to make this feature you just asked
to to make it work. But um but but the
other aspect is indeed maintainability.
It's indeed code duplication. It's all
these things that are sort of bad
practices
uh when it comes to sort of quality
software creation. Um, so I guess I'm
asking like I think you've you you did
it on your own in B 44 for your
codebase. How do you think about that in
terms of building applications
that are built by B 44 um to to have
longevity? So in two ways, one, when you
build an app in B 44 these days, like
there's a lot of infrastructure and
setup that happens before the LLM even
writes code
>> that in some ways limits it, but not
really, not in terms of like what it
needs to, but it's kind like it it those
are guardrails that the LLM should keep
>> and as long as it keeps that, then then
it should be fine to some degree. Um so
again we automatically create the entire
uh uh read update delete kind like the
CRUD SDK and and we make it like really
good and we implement like rate limits
on top of that and things like that that
LLMs wouldn't really care about
>> and when you leverage
um I don't know APIs and integrations
and so on like we kept a very strict
schema there's like a lot of things that
we implement mented built into the
application so that LLM won't kind like
be this reward seeking of like I'll do
whatever but I'll I'll keep your app
exposed and and so on. The other the
other thing is yes at some points uh we
automatically feedback the LLM whether
the user knows about it or not that it
needs to refactor something. So for
example, uh one of the things that makes
LLM confused the most um and people feel
that like across the the the vibe coding
category is uh when they're saying like
hey I asked it to do something it didn't
do it it did the opposite it deleted a
feature or whatever um is when code
files are are getting too long uh right
>> right if if like you've implemented so
you ask it initially or early on Hey,
implement this page, create a to-do list
up, and it did something simple. It's
like a very simple to-do list up like in
any other React and then start layering
in features, right? So, the LM does what
what you asked it to and and it start
adding like uh AI features to write the
tasks description and then user
management to like assign different
teams and boards and whatever. And at
some point, you have like if you're not
careful, you might have like this very
large code file. Right.
>> So one of the things is like we're
running behind the scenes refactoring
tests uh to maybe tell the LLM, hey like
you passed the threshold, you should now
refactor this file. Even if like okay
the user ask you something. First
refactor the file then implement what
the user has asked you to. And I think
like there's a lot more to do there. But
yeah, it's somewhat of like this uh code
quality agent that that's keep nudging
the LLM at some points if it finds that
it's past the first threshold of like
hey like there's this code here and this
code here like do something refactor
that
>> right yeah makes sense I think um a
couple of questions about specs and
tests so we um know we we talk a lot
about specs here it's kind of tessel's
uh uh kind of a claim for existence of
you know, products coming soon. Uh, and
uh, and you know, we I think in general
there's also like growing appreciation
in the in the world of AI development
that you want to capture knowledge
that's outside your code or summaries of
it and then test those as guard rails. I
guess how do you how have you used maybe
tests for sure and maybe specs uh, as
part of creation in B 44? People start
with tests even, right? like how do you
how do you think
>> tests? Uh I think just like
like the way you guys think at TESL I
think is like software is changing right
so some of the paradigms that we've
built uh throughout the years are not
really relevant anymore uh some of them
become like more relevant but even if
like if you look at the testdriven
development it will likely look like
look very different so in the first few
months of base 44
there were no unit tests.
Um there were like very different tests.
Uh so a lot of the tests were an actual
agent going into a browser opening up a
local host like a local version of B 44
tries different features and the way
that I'll write test would be like
prompts saying like hey when a user
first logs in with a new like and that's
a first user make sure this popup
exists. uh go into the like go into the
homepage, write a prompt, uh run it,
then uh you should see in in less than 3
minutes, you should see like this and
that. And so a lot of the tests that I
built early on inside B even for B 44 to
keep velocity high but still maintain a
quality piece of software or like end to
end tests um that are not even like
they're not written with code. It's like
more high level tell an agent go into a
browser and test it. Interesting. Is
that your reason for that? Was that just
sort of reality? You needed the end to
end tests anyway and then so you might
as well spare yourself the uh the need
to uh to create the unit tests or uh or
is it sort of some fundamental like I
don't think unit tests are right for it
because I don't care about the
implementation as much. So yeah, cuz
implementation changes and so I was
changing the code so much throughout the
day that like keeping a set of unit test
would have been more often a headache
>> than like uh that you constantly need to
refactor and you constantly and so what
you want to like at the end of the day
what you want to make sure is that your
code works and when when it doesn't that
you can easily get to the like what
doesn't work right that's some of the p
some of like the reason behind unit test
is like it's easier like to understand
oh this unit fails so you know where
even in the code is a problem that
you're having cuz otherwise like okay
just write as as many end to end flows
and if those work then your your
software does what what it should be
doing um and so I think that's why a lot
of like at the first few months when I
was refactoring so much I was like I
found this way of like doing end to end
test that really is scalable almost as
if you had like team of like manual QA
engineers
>> that you could go into your software and
change things. Obviously, if you want to
scale and you want to work inside a
team, unit tests are important. They're
like they're they're explaining some of
the things that that should happen with
your software and especially when
>> when back end becomes like really
uh large and complex.
Um,
>> so and these are this way that you found
to sort of run the end to end test. Was
that also AI powered? Is that sort of
browser based? Uh, hey find a button and
press the button and such as opposed to
telling it whatever the dome ID and when
you're absolutely and when you're
changing the UI a lot and so on and it's
more around the logic and AI agents
running browsers nowadays are pretty
good with the logic. So even if like
>> I remember like I remember UI testing
used to look like uh you'd have like
this um HTML selector like like a jQuery
selector well to find a button then you
change something the whole test would
break and you spend like 20 30 40% of
your time just refactoring the tests
after you change the UI a lot
>> and so yeah I think I'm still wrapping
my head around this. I'm not sure that
we're doing a great job with like
rethinking how uh things change as AI is
writing more and more code.
>> Yeah. I think also part of it is like
um part of like the reason why we
haven't I haven't built a lot of like
unit test starting on is is again AI
does a really good job with also
identifying if you tell it what the bug
is like it will search and it will try
and understand and you'll get really
fast to like where does this happens and
I think that's also part of the reason
why I haven't invested a lot of time in
unit test.
>> Yeah. Uh but I'm not sure this is like
the right
>> I'm like I have stronger opinions on on
other stuff. I'm not sure we've yet to
correct uh testing uh how it looks like
in this new new
>> and how uh how have you how do you think
about specs or sort of I guess docs are
the sort of the more core did you find
uh that you got benefit from creating
documentation in a more standard way uh
I guess what uh what has been the
>> yeah
um this is really interesting I think
angle and base as I see also a lot of
like the a lot of like base 44 users
sometimes I see what they're doing is
like they'll go and chat with chat GPD
they'll build like some sort of like a
pr or something like that or a spec of
like what they're looking to build um
and only then they'll upload it to base
44 because base 44 is slightly more uh
tipping towards action I'll say so even
if you say hey like let's shed repeat
about the app that that we want to build
and maybe we'll
>> yeah maybe we'll we'll add this stage
before creating an app like if you want
to just chat about it before and create
some uh spec and then make sure that
throughout time as you build your app
and adapt it and whatever like the LLM
constantly sees and validates that the
spec is still like still happening in
reality. Uh, I think that's also one of
like the top requested features that
I've yet to wrap my head around as to
how to approach it is like have some
sort of like a spec of what your app
should be doing. And then even if you
like when you ask the LLM to make it
prettier or change the button or add
functionality or whatever, it should
constantly get back to the spec and make
sure that it's not does not overrides or
changes anything because obviously
>> as as mo as many people know, this is
the biggest pain right now with VIP
coding. It's like you ask it to do one
thing or it might not entirely
understand you and and it did it but
messed up another thing or it didn't do
what exactly what you you wanted and so
yeah
>> again two places test and uh and specs
that I feel like we could be
>> the horizon you know both both on base
44 as its own app and and in the apps
created on top of it.
>> Yeah. Let me you you actually touched on
something I wanted to ask which is about
team members and so uh this has been
sort of super interesting. You built
them also you can zig and zag because
you know you're just you and so the LLM
changes you changed your opinion you
feel like a thing you don't need to
convince anybody else or align them. Uh
now you know postacquisition
>> um I guess maybe first it's a question
like how what do you anticipate will
happen? And I anticipate you have a plan
probably in terms of growing the team.
Do you still think, hey, we're going to
be three people, you know, we'll triple
the size of the team or uh or do you
think you're going to be 30? And then,
you know, how much how much is the
methodology that you've described
viable when it's a team that or multiple
teams that need to collaborate versus a
solo developer? like code thesis is that
uh
for building great software now you need
way smaller teams.
It's not actually that like it's
actually that if you're smaller you'll
be like it will be easier because when
you're smaller you have more context
right I'd rather have someone that knows
entirely the repository so that they can
change multiple things at once. Um
well the way I'm structuring the team
right now so is is keeping very lean and
efficient in terms of like team member
for every I don't know million or two
or3 dollars in in ARL
um and then having those team members
with as wide context as possible. So I
don't want any more of like this. Hey, I
built this part of the back end. Now I'm
going to hand it over to the other
person that will build the user
interface. We'll hand it over back to
build like a different thing. Oh, now we
have an info problem. So we need the
third guy. Um, and so I'm trying to
build a team very small. All of them
have like a lot of context. And the way
that I'm trying to manage the tasks is
isolate as much as possible and like
have every person to work almost like as
an individual. So take like big chunks
of your product, hand it over to this
person. This person is going to work
mostly alone. Um it's like I don't want
I want to see very few team meetings of
like sinking on something because like
you can now again every person becomes
like if you hire a 10x engineer nowadays
there are thousandx engineers because
>> they can like throw as many AI coding
agents as as as they want and it's not
anymore about oh this this task is
really big so I should be putting like
four or five people on it because again
it's not anymore about the amount code
that every person writes like say you
can write as much code as you want it
to.
>> Yeah. It's
>> there's probably still a case for like
for pairs uh in in the sense at least
for a single like someone goes on
vacation, right? or
>> or leaves the company or such then one
person sounds makes me like a little bit
uncomfortable but uh but I get the point
about tiny teams you know that's a
>> I agree and also like it's very hard to
find people that are also they're
awesome with back end but they also
understand some design and they also
understand some like front end concepts
and so on but as much as I can I'm
trying to like keep a small team and
Then the way they operate is like divide
and conquer.
>> Yeah. So, so and you anticipate them
working in the same fashion give or
take. Uh and the solution to that is is
architecture. Uh and and just set up.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Which uh again is actually not
new. It's actually you know the way that
you would scale you know the Amazon sort
of two pizza teams. When I think about
how we build Tesla, it is about okay
having software boundaries, having data
model boundaries, and eventually even
aiming to to allow timeline independence
of being able to ship whenever it is
that you ship. And all of those are
never perfectly correct, but they are um
they they are aspirational like you want
to invest in ensuring those lines are
are there and that makes sense. Um
>> yeah, I agree with
>> let's maybe be off. So we're kind of
like tight on time here on it. Maybe we
uh should we talk a little bit futures
like where this like we talked a lot
about sort of you know past and present
and I think we talked about like near
future. Um maybe I'll start with the big
question of like what do you what do you
envision developers being you know in in
in one year three year five year
horizons like what um what is still in
the realm of a developer um you know
what do you think just entirely goes
away? Yeah, obviously I I measure it as
like the percentage of software that
could be built today with tools like
base 44 and and other tools in the
category. Um,
and again I want to differentiate
between the the cursor and cloud code of
the world that are obviously targeting
developers, semi-developers,
uh, versus like the base 44s of the
world that that are targeting like the
everyday architect, lawyer, physician.
>> Yeah, they're expanding the definition
of a developer, right? Know you're
taking coding as literacy to to a
different place. And it's not coding as
literacy, it's software creation as
literacy. it is about making it
available to everybody.
>> Yes, absolutely. So, I think there
obviously the percentage of of software
that could be built uh is going to
increase tremendously.
Um, two places that I find that that
really at least I'm putting a lot of
focus on is on the enterprise side. Uh,
so again, if I'm putting it on like a
timeline, so coding has started building
great websites. It was really fun to see
that you can build a landing page, maybe
some interaction, but great with front
end.
>> Um, and then base 44 targeted a lot of
like build a functional app like a
project management tool, CRM, invoice
management apps, stuff like that.
>> Um, seeing now more and more
organizations
adopt B 44 to build like internal tools,
to build back office systems, to build
like things that they used to like pay a
lot for like custom software. Um and
then so there's two vectors that we
really need to get better at like as a
category. One is the enterprise side of
things like build enterprisegrade
applications
uh that could really transform the way
organizations are being built. Every
large organization has tons of software
needs and I think like a small
percentage of it is like customerf
facing. Uh
>> but a lot of it is like think of an
organization like I don't know Pepsi or
something like that like how much
software do they need internally to run
this uh to this business and the more
the marrier right the more that you
build tools the more that you build
automations uh the more that the
business becomes more efficient
>> um so there's a lot that yeah
>> challenge like I don't actually want to
challenge that I agree with it but I
think there is a thesis that says um yes
a lot of like the uh enterprise
automation is a massive opportunity.
Just think about how much grunt work
happens and how much inefficiency
happens that if you could just easily
create software to create will make it
go away. But there's there is a thesis
that says uh well you wouldn't create
applications you would just delegate
those tasks to agents and so you
wouldn't create code that that lives as
an application the way we perceive it
today.
>> You would more outsource it to AI. So
that's the second thing which is um
lately I've been telling the team that
uh vibe coding is awesome obviously made
me rich but uh it's currently great at
building software the way it used to
look pre20223
when chipd came out um it's still very
hard to build a agentic applications um
and I I think a lot of like the value in
software and the latest like
groundbreaking software and base 44 is a
good example of that is going to become
like aic software. Um and I think we'll
find that it's not only chat and like
connect tools there's like something to
correct there. Uh you can see that in
coding agents in the UIX and whatever
it's like um there's some interaction
but it's a different kind of software.
So the second thing that that uh base 44
is going to invest a whole lot in and
we'll see a lot of like updates in the
near future is helping everyone build
agentic software. Uh an Agentic software
could be a software like B 44. It could
be that the CRM that you just fcoded now
has an embedded agent that can research
leads, can send you some updates before
a meeting, can enrich some data. It can
be that the support ticketing system
that you've built internally for your
SAS company will now have an agent that
auto replies and get trained on like
human responses and you'll be able to
actually vibe code uh this whole
application and so yeah I agree with you
definitely I think there's like a
combination of like things that like
enterprise grade you need either way
whether you're building a nice looking
uh web app or an actual agentic web
application. Uh but yeah the other thing
is like taking VIP coding to the place
where you can build great agentic
applications.
>> So with all of these advancements and
all the capabilities that B 44 is
building like what's your prediction
about how long does it take till you can
build a base 44 with B 44?
Um
that's a good question and it also has
to do with like
how
like how much will be we will be able to
crack this a gentic application thing.
Um,
my guess is like a fully functional base
44 app with like payments and credits
and like actually coding agents that are
coding like websites inside and so on.
>> Uh, about six months.
>> Six months
>> maybe less. Yeah. I'm looking like I'm
looking at sometimes it's like uh I'm
looking at the state of where vibe
coding and base 44 specifically was at
six months ago when it was
>> terrible.
>> Yeah. And so I think six months maybe
less. Uh definitely I would say not more
than a year.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean it's a good it's it's
a bold claim but it's a it's one that I
can I can get behind. And I think I also
think that uh it it not anybody could
create a base 44 like you you need
certain sort of skills and competences
to be able to achieve it but maybe you
can use it with those tools. Um and I
guess in that context like what is uh
the long-term differentiation you know
for a platform like base 44 given this
prediction
>> you know yesterday I I think yesterday
or two days ago I tweeted about
something that that was like insane to
me where we changed like one line of
code it's like change the string and we
move the 400k
uh workload flowed for like $400,000
from one LLM vendor to another and I was
like where's the mo like this is insane
cuz like you see those companies and
they're really growing like nicely but
where is this all headed if if
everything becomes a commodity and maybe
models at some point become a commodity
so I think the model layer is in
slightly more problematic way I wouldn't
even I wouldn't actually call it
problematic it's just it's very easy to
switch so there's no real mode but the
top players are just printing cash.
>> Yeah.
>> And so I think
>> it's hard to enter that group now and
move between the group but it's harder
to imagine someone I
>> entering the group now.
>> Yeah. But it's going to be it's going to
be a very interesting
um market because it's unlike uh the
cloud uh let's say vendor. So obviously
it's also a very hard uh uh ticket to
get in but but it's also very hard to
switch between clouds, right? It's very
hard to take your entire setup from
Microsoft Azure to AWS. This won't be
the case between models because
like when a new model comes out and it's
slightly better, then for me it's like
yeah, I'm going to spend like five
minutes and change the and move like
hundreds of thousands of dollars a month
uh and probably in the future even more
from one vendor to another. Um
where is the moat? There's many places.
So one just being ahead, right? If
you're four months ahead of the
competition these days, it's it's very
important, right? So, I I know Yeah,
>> I know that some of the some of B 44's
competitors are going to come up with
like a built-in back end and batteries
included kind of like approach of like
is seeing kind like what it does to base
44's users, but at that point we'll
already be like further ahead. Um and so
yeah, just velocity is the I think the
number one um mode, but there's also
brand distribution, community. I think B
44 is lucky to have the strongest
community that I've seen. Uh it's like
users are absolutely fantastic and they
help each other. Um,
and yeah, there's still some places
where
a unique product take that's hard to
replicate
um is insanely important. Uh so if you
can like again for me and not to sound
too cocky but like I was like okay
there's this problem with building
functional apps in vibe coding and for
building for like the nontechnical
person I can envision how this
experience should look like they should
just type something they don't need to
understand what the database is or
whatever everything will be built and
then translating that into how to
implement that from a tech perspective
uh and in a scalable day cuz like people
build I think tens of thousands of apps
a day uh nowadays and so how do you
scale that and and hold this whole thing
and the back end and whatever like how
do you do that
>> there's still some technical mode
>> velocity like make good decisions and
execute on them fast
>> yeah and and it's the same thing right
yeah it's the same thing is if you make
good decisions and great decisions from
an architectural standpoint then your
velocity will be
>> right
>> so I think that's a that's a big mode
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It's good. Sounds like
a a
great kind of uh equal cry almost like
you do have the brand, you do have the
distribution. So, especially now within
weeks and so it's not
>> um it's not an equal playing ground. Uh
but it is uh more equal maybe than ever
before uh as you've uh as you've
demonstrated. Um, so I guess maybe just
as a a final uh question here, what's
the sort of the top advice you'd have
for developers listening uh to this
podcast like as they as they brace
themselves to the sort of insanity that
is engulfing us uh and change? What's
what's sort of the top advice for
developer today? Um the way I think the
future is headed is that people who
can jump between domains so at least
understand a little bit between domain
so that they can execute with AI agents
uh things end to end will be more
successful than the people who are
currently very deep into something. Uh
so there's like a great
front end developers that understand the
ins and outs of of React. I think that
won't be as valuable
as people who can execute end to end
again together with AI agents and have
some understanding of front end great
understanding of back end some
understanding of of design some
understanding of like UI and can take
something either feature or build a
product themselves and can lead that end
to end. So my advice for for I think for
developers and what I'm advising some of
my friends is like take a step back go
and build something end to end. It will
teach you more about the other places
that you haven't touched yet like
product and design and and users and
community and whatever. Uh depends on on
where you're at and what type of
developer uh you are. Um but take a step
back try to build something uh because I
think the future will belong to uh
people who have some understanding cost
domains um because then you'll have AI
agents specializing and and deeper
understanding of syntax
>> is not an advantage anymore like those
agents will know the LLMs will know way
better than us what's the latest and
greatest packages how to use them what's
the syntax and so on
>> right yeah super super interesting. You
know, basically like elevate yourself up
uh the the list and you know we talk
about you need to either move up the
product manager route of understand
product better or move up the architect
route of sort of understand sort of
system architecture but either way you
have to broaden uh the perspective
>> more uh this was excellent. Thanks a lot
for coming on to the show. Massive
congrats on on the incredible journey
which I understand is just beginning.
Still a lot of work ahead uh which I
look forward to to following. But thanks
uh thanks for coming here and sharing
all these insights.
>> Thank you guys. This has been awesome.
>> Uh and thanks everyone for tuning in and
I hope you join us for the next one.
[Music]